Finding Aid for Plant Extension Services (University of Michigan) Records, 1907-1996
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Plant Extension Services (University of Michigan) records 1907-1996
University of Michigan. Plant Extension Services.
20 tubes blueprint tubes
3 linear feet
87327 Bimu B27 2
Records, 1907-1996, of Plant Extension Services, liaison unit concerned with the monitoring of new construction projects and the expansion and renovation of existing buildings at the University of Michigan. Minutes of construction meetings, summary financial statements, site and building plans and proposals, blueprints, and visual materials; including files relating to the Detroit Observatory and the Natural Science Building; include undated sketch of North Campus, unsigned, but attributed to Eero Saarinen.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records of the unit were transferred to the library in several accessions beginning in 1982 (donor nos. 6751 and 5582 ). 6751
The record group is open without restriction.
Established in 1929/1930, the Plant Extension Services serves as a liaison between university units responsible for financial accountability and Construction Engineering, Engineering Services, the University Architect's office and the University Planner's office, all of who report to Plant Extension. The primary responsibility of this group of offices is monitoring and coordinating new construction as well as the expansion and renovation of existing buildings.
Plant Extension office records include detailed minutes of construction meetings, monthly reports, summary financial statements, site and building plans and proposals, and blueprints. The material is arranged alphabetically, usually by building name. Among the blueprints are files relating to the Detroit Observatory and the Natural Science Building and an undated sketch of North Campus, unsigned, but attributed to Eero Saarinen
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Administration.; University of Michigan--Buildings.; University of Michigan--Campus.; University of Michigan. Detroit Observatory.; University of Michigan. Plant Extension Services.; Natural Science Building (University of Michigan); North Campus (University of Michigan); Saarinen, Eero, 1910-1961.
Genre Terms:
Architectural drawings.; Videotapes.
- Records
  - Architect's/Planner's monthly reports 1974-1977 (Box 1)
  - Argus I Amphibian Facility (Box 1)
  - Business Administration Paton Center Construction (Box 1)
  - Camp Filibert Roth-Sewage Disposal System (Box 1)
  - Central Campus Planning Study 1963 (Box 1)
  - Central Campus Recreation Building (Box 1)
  - Chemistry Stores Construction (Box 1)
  - Construction Engineering monthly reports 1973-1978 (Box 1)
  - Detroit Observatory 1907-1909
    - Detroit Observatory 1907-1909 (Tube 1)
    - Detroit Observatory 1907-1909 (Tube 2)
      (continued)
    - Detroit Observatory 1907-1909 (Tube 3)
  - DNA Laboratory Renovations (Box 1)
  - Economics Building Renovations
    - 1910 (Tube 4)
    - 1974-1975, 1 folder (Box 1)
    - 1974-1975 (Tube 5)
  - Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (EECS) Building (Box 1)
  - Engineering Building I-A (Box 1)
  - Engineering Services monthly reports 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - General Stores Study and General Stores Renovation (Box 1)
  - Graduate Library
    - 1916 (Tube 6)
    - 1973-1975 (Box 1)
  - Health Professions Education Facilities Study (Box 1)
  - Henderson Memorial House 1941 (Tube 7)
  - Henry Ford Estate (Fairlane) (Tube 8)
  - Hospital Administration Building and Parking Structure Construction
    - General (Box 1)
    - Renovations
      - 7th Level Operating Room (Box 1)
      - 5th, 7th and 9th Level (Box 1)
      - 11th Level (Box 1)
      - Physical Configuration Task Force (Box 1)
      - Long Range Planning (Chi Systems, Inc.) (Box 1)
      - Design Guidance Study and Facilities Development Planning Committee (Box 1)
      - Functional and Space Programming (Box 1)
  - Ingliss House 1928 (Tube 9)
  - Institute for Social Research (Box 2)
  - Landscape Architect's Office monthly reports (Box 2)
  - C.C. Little Ventilation Survey April 1977 (Box 2)
  - Medical Center Building Survey 1971, 3 volumes (Box 2)
  - Michigan Student Assembly (Box 2)
  - Michigan Student Assembly Space Requests (Box 2)
  - Michigan Union 1917
    - Michigan Union 1917 (Tube 10)
    - Michigan Union 1917 (Tube 11)
  - Natural Science Building 1914
    - Natural Science Building 1914 (Tube 12)
    - Natural Science Building 1914 (Tube 13)
    - Natural Science Building 1914 (Tube 14)
  - Naval Architecture and Marine Engineering Building Addition (Box 2)
  - Natural Science Renovation (Colvin Robinson reports) (Box 2)
  - North Campus Recreation Building Construction (Box 2)
  - Occupational Safety, Environmental Health monthly reports 1973-1976 (Box 2)
  - Plant Protection 1941-1950 (Box 2)
  - Planting Diagrams 1910-1938
    - Planting Diagrams 1910-1938 (Tube 15)
    - Planting Diagrams 1910-1938 (Tube 16)
  - Pound House (Trueblood Residence) (Tube 17)
  - Power Plant
    - Balance Condenser (Box 2)
    - Turbine Generator (Box 2)
  - Public Works Act (Box 2)
  - Recreational Facilities (Box 2)
  - The Scott Amy Prudden Turner Memorial Clinic (Box 3)
    - Meeting Notes (Box 3)
    - Construction 1973-1980, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Stockwell Dormitory 1939-1940 (Tube 18)
  - Student Army Training Corp. (SATC) 1918-1926 (Box 3)
  - Tunnels (Tube 20)
  - University Survey circa 1950 (Box 3)
  - Willow Run Airport Master Plan 1966 (Box 3)
  - Women's Athletic Building
    - 1911 (Tube 19)
    - Demolition (Box 3)
- VHS Videocassette Tapes
  - An Historical Perspective of Central Campus and the Ingalls Mall 1991 (Box 3)
  - Outdoor Sculptures on Campus 1991 (Box 3)
  - The University of Michigan Integrated Technology Instruction Center 1996 (Box 3)
- Accretions since 1980
  - Study of Reuse of the Old Main Hospital (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Undergraduate Library Photographs, 1955-1958 (Box 3)